In this video, we are going to be installing our DNS server.
So here, as you can see, we have a difference in error.
First of all, I have my domain controller which is a DC01 and I also have a secondary domain
controller which is the DC02, so my primary domain controller is a DC01, here you can see
we have the DC01 and the DC02, both are actually configured with the DNS server.
Here, you can see we have our DNS, that's the DC01 and the DC02.
Thirdly, I'm going to configure it.
Third DNS, which is going to be actually a standalone DNS server.
So by mind, you haven't actually multiple DNS server, it's very, very important if you are
walking for a big company, should it give something good wrong with one of your server, your
second server will still be available to help you that users should still be able to assess
your website, or assess domains, and so forth.
So for example, right now, you can see we have for example, here we have the 4 look-up zone
and also have the 4 look-up zone, everything is actually being replicated and if I go click
on my 4 look-up zone, you can see we have a kelblubout.com and the same thing on our
secondary server will have a kelblubout.com.
Now, we want to install a standalone DNS server, what you need to do right now is to go to our
DNS server and here we are going to be adding rules and future.
So right now, let us click Nest and in this select installation type, we're just going
to click.
It's going to be a rule-based or future-based installation, so click Nest and we are going
to be doing it on this server, does they check if the IP address is correct and then click
Nest.
All right now, what you want to do is you see, it's asking what we want to apply, install
which rules we want to install.
We want to install the DNS server rules, so these are the other features that will be added
to it, just click add futures and then click Nest, and then we're going to click Nest
and then we need to install.
So the installation is about to take long time, so let me just pause this video and come
back again when installation, installation, complete.
So right now, you can see that it says the installation succeeded on our server, so let's
just click close and we don't have any other task we need to perform, that installation
of our DNS rules.
So what you need to do right now is to go and just here we have our tools and then let's
just click the Nest.
You can see, this is actually that the host name of our, the other name of our device,
you can see that the DNS server has just been installed, and at this moment you can see
we don't have any, see the four look-up zone, at this moment you can see it's when we've
seen any information.
So what we need to do, we need to actually allow our device from our main domain server
to allow that this is 01, to actually replicate to this server and add the IP address of
this server to that server so that the server will be able to retrieve all the four look-ups
on the reverse look-ups zone, conditional for us from main server.
And also, you can actually install your DNS rules using the following PowerShell command.
If for example, if I just go to my start menu and enter PowerShell, I don't switch to that
PowerShell, there we go, let me just launch the PowerShell eC as an administrator.
So let's enter the following command from our PowerShell, get Windows, future, and the name
the game to be DNS.
So we'll enter that, you can see that this is the DNS server is installed.
But if the DNS, for example, we then use our server manager to actually add the rules,
we cannot actually use PowerShell by entering the following command, install Windows, future,
and the name is going to be DNS, and then you're going to do include the tools.
And then you can just hit enter.
So at this point, you can see it says no, because the installation has been DNS rules
have been installed, so it's not going to install it for the second time.
But mind you, if you've not installed it using server manager, you cannot use the Windows
PowerShell to perform this installation.